I'm really, really excited about this lecture,
我对这次演讲非常兴奋，
because as Alexander introduced yesterday,
因为正如 Alexander 昨天介绍的那样，
right now we're in this tremendous age of generative AI,
现在我们正处于一个生成性人工智能的巨大时代，
and today we're going to learn the foundations of deep generative modeling,
今天我们将学习深度生成性建模的基础，
where we're going to talk about building systems,
在那里我们将讨论建立系统，
that can not only look for patterns in data,
不仅可以在数据中寻找模式，
but can actually go a step beyond this
而且实际上可以更进一步，
to generate brand new data instances based on those learned patterns,
基于这些学习的模式生成全新的数据实例，
this is an incredibly complex and powerful idea,
这是一个令人难以置信的复杂和强大的想法，
and as I mentioned,
就像我提到的，
it's a particular subset of deep learning,
这是深度学习的一个特殊子集，
that has actually really exploded in the past couple of years and this year in particular.
在过去几年里真的发生了爆炸式的增长，特别是今年。
So to start, and to demonstrate how powerful these algorithms are,
所以，为了演示这些算法的强大功能，
let me show you these three different faces,
让我向你们展示一下这三张不同的脸，
I want you to take a minute think,
我想让你想一想，
think about which face you think is real,
想想你认为哪张脸是真的，
raise your hand, if you think it's face A,
如果你认为是脸 A ，请举手，
okay, see a couple of people,
好的，看到几个人，
Face B,
脸 B ，
many more people,
更多的人，
face C,
脸 C ，
second place,
第二名，
well, the truth is that all of you are wrong,
好的，事实是你们都错了，
all three of these faces are fake,
这三张脸都是假的，
these people do not exist,
这些人并不存在，
these images were synthesized by deep generative models,
这些图像是由深度生成模型合成的，
trained on data of human faces
基于人脸数据进行训练，
and asked to produce new instances.
并要求生成新的实例。
Now, I think that this demonstration kind of demonstrates the power of these ideas
现在，我认为这个演示展示了这些想法的力量，
and the power of this notion of generative modeling.
和生成性建模概念的力量。
So let's get a little more concrete about how we can formalize this.
所以，让我们更具体地了解如何将这件事正规化。
So far in this course,
到目前为止，在这门课程中，
we've been looking at what we call problems of supervised learning,
我们一直在研究我们所说的监督学习问题，
meaning that we're given data
这意味着我们给出数据，
and associated with that data is a set of labels,
并与这些数据相关联的是一组标签，
our goal is to learn a function that maps that data to the labels,
我们的目标是学习映射该数据的标签的函数，
Now, we're in a course on deep learning,
现在我们在一门关于深度学习的课程，
so we've been concerned with functional mappings that are defined by deep neural networks,
所以我们一直关注由深度神经网络定义的函数映射，
but really, that function could be anything,
但实际上，这个函数可以是任何东西，
neural networks are powerful,
神经网络很强大，
but we could use other techniques as well.
但我们也可以使用其他技术。
In contrast, there's another class of problems in machine learning,
相比之下，在机器学习中还有另一类问题，
that we refer to as unsupervised learning,
我们称之为无监督学习，
where we take data,
我们获取数据，
but now we're given only data, no labels,
但现在我们只给出数据，没有标签，
and our goal is to try to build some method,
我们的目标是试图建立某种方法，
that can understand the hidden underlying structure of that data,
可以理解这些数据的隐藏的底层结构，
what this allows us to do is,
这使我们能够做的是，
it gives us new insights into the foundational representation of the data
它让我们对数据的基本表示形式有了新的见解，
and as we'll see later,
并且正如我们稍后将看到的那样，
actually enables us to generate new data instances.
使我们能够生成新的数据实例。
Now, this class of problems,
现在，这类问题，
this definition of unsupervised learning,
无监督学习的定义，
captures the types of models that we're going to talk about today
抓住了我们今天要讨论的模型类型，
in the focus on generative modeling,
重点是生成性建模，
which is an example of unsupervised learning
这是无监督学习的一个例子，
and is united by this goal of the problem,
它与这个问题的目标相一致，
where we're given only samples from a training set,
在这个问题中，我们只得到训练集中的样本，
and we want to learn a model,
我们想要学习一种模型，
that represents the distribution of the data that the model is seeing.
表示该模型所看到的数据的分布。
Generative modeling takes two general forms,
生成式建模一般有两种形式，
first, density estimation
第一种是密度估计，
and second, sample generation.
第二种是样本生成。
In density estimation,
在密度估计中，
the task is given some data examples,
任务是给出一些数据实例，
our goal is to train a model,
我们的目标是训练一个模型，
that learns an underlying probability distribution,
学习潜在概率分布，
that describes where the data came from.
描述了数据来源。
With sample generation,
对于样本生成，
the idea is similar,
想法是相似的，
but the focus is more on actually generating new instances,
但重点更多地放在生成新实例上，
our goal with sample generation is to,
我们生成样本的目标是，
again, learn this model of this underlying probability distribution,
再次，学习这种潜在概率分布的模型，
but then use that model to sample from it
然后使用该模型对其进行采样，
and generate new instances,
并生成新的实例，
that are similar to the data that we've seen,
类似于我们看到的数据，
approximately falling along, ideally that same real data distribution.
大致下降，理想情况下，相同的真实数据分布。
Now, in both these cases of density estimation and sample generation,
现在，在密度估计和样本生成这两种情况下，
the underlying question is the same,
潜在的问题都是相同的，
our learning task is to try to build a model,
我们的学习任务是尝试建立一个模型，
that learns this probability distribution,
学习这种概率分布，
that is as close as possible to the true data distribution.
尽可能接近真实的数据分布。
Okay, so with this definition and this concept of generative modeling,
好的，有了这个生成性建模的定义和概念，
what are some ways that we can actually deploy generative modeling
我们可以用什么方法部署生成式模型，
forward in the real world for high impact applications,
在现实世界中为高影响的应用程序，
well, part of the reason that generative models are so powerful is,
好的，生成式模型是如此强大的部分原因是，
that they have this ability to uncover the underlying features in a dataset
它们有能力发现数据集中的底层特征，
and encode it in an efficient way.
并以有效的方式对其进行编码。
So, for example, if we're considering the problem of facial detection
例如，如果我们考虑面部检测问题，
and we're given a dataset with many, many different faces,
我们得到一个包含许多不同人脸的数据集，
starting out without inspecting this data,
而没有检查这些数据，
we may not know what the distribution of faces in this dataset is,
我们可能不知道这个数据集中人脸的分布是什么，
with respect to features we may be caring about,
相对于我们可能关心的特征，
for example the pose of the head, clothing, glasses, skin tone, hair, etc,
例如，头部的姿势、衣服、眼镜、肤色、头发等，
and it can be the case,
情况可能是，
that our training data may be very, very biased towards particular features
我们的训练数据可能对特定的特征非常有偏见，
without us even realizing this,
在我们甚至没有意识到的情况下，
using generative models,
使用生成模型，
we can actually identify the distributions of these underlying features
我们可以识别这些潜在特征的分布，
in a completely automatic way without any labeling,
以一种完全自动的方式，而不需要任何标记，
in order to understand what features may be overrepresented in the data,
为了了解哪些特征在数据中可能被高估，
what features may be underrepresented in the data.
哪些特征在数据中可能被低估。
And this is the focus of today and tomorrow's software labs,
这是今天和明天软件实验的重点，
which are going to be part of the software lab competition,
将成为软件实验竞争的一部分，
developing generative models that can do this task
开发可以完成这项任务的生成性模型，
and using it to uncover and diagnose biases,
并使用它来发现和诊断偏差，
that can exist within facial detection models.
面部检测模型中可能存在的（偏差）。
Another really powerful example is,
另一个真正强大的例子是，
in the case of outlier detection, identifying rare events.
在异常值检测的情况下，识别罕见事件。
So, let's consider the example of self driving autonomous cars,
所以，让我们来考虑自动驾驶汽车的例子，
with an autonomous car, let's say it's driving out in the real world,
有了自动驾驶汽车，假设它正在现实世界中行驶，
we really really want to make sure that,
我们真的很想确保，
that car can be able to handle all the possible scenarios
这辆车能够处理所有可能的情况，
and all the possible cases it may encounter,
和它可能遇到的所有可能的情况，
including edge cases like a deer coming in front of the car
包括边缘情况，比如鹿走到车前面，
or some unexpected rare events,
或一些意想不到的罕见事件，
not just, you know, the typical straight freeway driving,
而不仅仅是典型的直线行驶，
that it may see the majority of the time.
它可能会在大部分时间看到的。
With generative models,
对于生成模型，
we can use this idea of density estimation
我们可以使用这种密度估计的思想
to be able to identify rare and anomalous events within the training data
来识别训练数据中的罕见和异常事件，
and as they're occurring,
以及当它们发生时，
as the model sees them, for the first time.
就像模型第一次看到它们一样。
So hopefully this paints this picture of what generative modeling the underlying concept is,
希望这幅图描绘了什么是生成性建模的基本概念，
and a couple of different ways
以及几种不同的方式，
in which we can actually deploy these ideas for powerful and impactful real world applications.
我们可以将这些想法实际部署到强大而有效的现实世界应用程序中。
In today's lecture, we're going to focus on a broad class of generative models,
在今天的课程中，我们将重点介绍一大类生成性模型，
that we call latent variable models
我们称之为隐变量模型，
and specifically distill down into two subtypes of latent variable models.
具体分为两种类型的隐变量模型。
First things, first, I've introduced this term latent variable,
首先，我已经引入了隐变量这个术语，
but I haven't told you or described to you what that actually is,
但是我还没有告诉你们或者描述它到底是什么，
I think a great example,
我认为一个很好的例子，
and one of my favorite examples throughout this entire course,
也是我在整个课程中最喜欢的一个例子，
that gets at this idea of the latent variable,
获得隐变量的思想，
is this little story from Plato's republic,
就是这个来自柏拉图的理想国的小故事，
which is known as the myth of the cave,
这就是众所周知的洞穴寓言，
in this myth,
在这个寓言中，
there is a group of prisoners,
有一群囚犯，
and as part of their punishment,
作为惩罚的一部分，
they're constrained to face a wall,
他们被迫面对一堵墙，
now the only things that prisoners can observe are
现在囚犯们唯一能观察到的东西是，
shadows of objects that are passing in front of a fire that's behind them,
在他们身后的火堆前经过的物体的阴影，
and they're observing the casting of the shadows on the wall of this cave,
他们观察这个洞穴墙上的阴影的投射，
to the prisoners,
对于囚犯来说，
those shadows are the only things they see,
这些阴影是他们唯一看到的东西，
their observations, they can measure them,
他们的观察，他们可以测量他们，
they can give them names,
他们可以给他们起名字，
because to them that's their reality,
因为对他们来说，这就是他们的现实，
but they're unable to directly see the underlying objects,
但他们不能直接看到潜在的物体，
the true factors themselves, that are casting those shadows,
真实的因素本身，这些因素投射那些阴影，
those objects here are like latent variables in machine learning,
这里的这些对象就像机器学习中的隐变量，
they're not directly observable,
它们不是直接可见的，
but they are the true underlying features or explanatory factors,
但它们是真正的潜在特征或解释因素，
that create the observed differences and variables that we can see and observe.
它们创造了我们可以看到和观察到的差异和变量。
And this gets at the goal of generative modeling,
这就达到了生成性建模的目标，
which is to find ways that we can actually learn these hidden features,
即找到方法让我们能够真正学习这些隐藏的特征，
these underlying latent variables,
这些潜在的隐变量，
even when we're only given observations of the observed data.
即使我们只得到了观察到的数据。
So let's start by discussing a very simple generative model,
所以，让我们从讨论一个非常简单的生成性模型开始，
that tries to do this through the idea of encoding the data input,
试图通过对数据输入进行编码来实现这一点，
the models we're going to talk about are called autoencoders,
我们将要讨论的模型被称为自编码器，
and to take a look at how an autoencoder works,
为了看看自编码器是如何工作的，
we'll go through step by step,
我们将一步一步地来，
starting with the first step of taking some raw input data
从获取一些原始输入数据开始，
and passing it through a series of neural network layers,
并将其传递给一系列神经网络层，
now, the output of this, of this first step is what we refer to as a low dimensional latent space,
现在，这第一步的输出就是我们所说的低维隐空间，
it's an encoded representation of those underlying features,
它是这些基本特征的编码表示，
and that's our goal in trying to train this model and predict those features,
这就是我们试图训练这个模型并预测这些特征的目标，
the reason a model like this is called an encoder or an autoencoder
这样的模型之所以被称为编码器或自编码器，
is that it's mapping the data X into this vector of latent variables z.
是因为它将数据 x 映射到隐变量 z 的向量中。
Now, let's ask ourselves a question,
现在，让我们问自己一个问题，
let's pause for a moment,
让我们暂停一下，
why may we care about having this latent variable vector z be in a low dimensional space,
为什么我们可能会关心这个隐变量向量 z 在低维空间，
anyone have any ideas?
有谁有什么想法吗？
Alright, maybe there are some ideas, yes.
好的，也许有一些想法，是的。
The suggestion was that it's more efficient,
建议是，这样做效率更高，
yes, that gets at it,
是的，这就是问题所在，
the heart of the, of the question.
这个问题的核心。
The idea of having that low dimensional latent space is that,
拥有低维隐空间的想法是，
it's a very efficient, compact encoding of the rich, high dimensional data,
它是对丰富的、高维数据的一种非常有效、紧凑的编码，
that we may start with.
我们可以从它开始。
As you pointed out, what this means is that,
正如你所指出的，这意味着，
we're able to compress data into this small feature representation of vector,
我们能够将数据压缩为向量的小特征表示形式，
that captures this compactness and richness
这抓住了这种紧凑性和丰富性，
without requiring so much memory or so much storage.
而不需要如此多的内存或存储空间。
So how do we actually train the network to learn this latent variable vector,
那么，我们如何训练网络来学习这个隐变量向量呢，
since we don't have training data,
由于我们没有训练数据，
we can't explicitly observe these latent variables x,
我们不能显式地观察这些潜在的变量 z ，
we need to do something more clever,
我们需要做一些更聪明的事情，
what the autoencoder does is
自编码器所做的是，
it builds a way to decode this latent variable vector back up to the original data space,
它建立一种方法，将这个隐变量向量解码回到原始数据空间，
trying to reconstruct the original image from that compressed, efficient latent encoding.
试图从压缩的、高效的隐编码中重建原始图像。
And once again, we can use a series of neural network layers,
再次，我们可以使用一系列神经网络层，
such as convolutional layers, fully connected layers,
比如卷积层，完全连接层，
but now to map back from that lower dimensional space back upwards to the input space,
但现在要从低维空间向上映射回输入空间，
this generates a reconstructed output, which we can denote as x hat,
这会生成重建的输出，我们可以将其表示为 x hat ，
since it's an imperfect reconstruction of our original input data.
因为它是原始输入数据的不完美重建。
To train this network,
要训练这个网络，
all we have to do is
我们所要做的就是，
compare the outputted reconstruction and the original input data
比较输出的重建数据和原始的输入数据，
and say, how do we make these as similar as possible,
然后说，我们如何使它们尽可能地相似，
we can minimize the distance between that input and our reconstructed output.
我们可以最小化输入和重构输出之间的距离。
So, for example, for an image,
例如，对于一幅图像，
we can compare the pixel wise difference between the input data and the reconstructed output,
我们可以比较输入数据和重建输出之间的像素差异，
just subtracting the images from one another and squaring that difference
只需将图像彼此相减并对差异平方，
to capture the pixel wise divergence between the input and the reconstruction.
捕捉输入和重建之间的像素差异。
What I hope you'll notice and appreciate is
我希望你能注意和理解的是，
in that definition of the loss,
在损失的定义中，
it doesn't require any labels,
它不需要任何标签，
the only components of that loss are
损失的唯一组成部分是，
the original input data x and the reconstructed output x hat.
原始输入数据 x 和重建的输出 x hat 。
So I've simplified now this diagram
所以我现在已经简化了这个图，
by abstracting away those individual neural network layers
通过抽象出那些单独的神经网络层，
in both the encoder and decoder components of this.
在这个的编码器和解码器组件中。
And again, this idea of not requiring any labels gets back to the idea of unsupervised learning,
再次，这个不需要任何标签的想法回到了无监督学习的想法，
since what we've done is we've been able to learn an encoded quantity, our latent variables,
因为我们所做的是我们能够学习一个编码量，我们的隐变量，
that we cannot observe without any explicit labels,
我们无法在没有任何显式标签的情况下观察到，
all we started from was the raw data itself.
我们从原始数据本身开始。
It turns out that as as the question and answer got out,
事实证明，只要问题和答案出来，
that dimensionality of the latent space has a huge impact
隐空间的维度就会产生巨大的影响，
on the quality of the generated reconstructions and how compressed that information bottleneck is.
对生成的重建的质量和信息瓶颈的压缩程度。
Autoencoding is a form of compression,
自动编码是压缩的一种形式，
and so the lower the dimensionality of the latent space,
因此隐空间的维度越低，
the less good our reconstructions are going to be,
我们的重建效果就越差，
but the higher the dimensionality,
但维度越高，
the more, the less efficient that encoding is going to be.
编码的效率就越低。
So to summarize this first part,
所以总结第一部分，
this idea of an autoencoder is using this bottleneck, compressed, hidden latent layer
这个自编码器的想法是利用这个瓶颈，压缩的，隐藏的隐层，
to try to bring the network down to learn a compact, efficient representation of the data,
来试图降低网络，以学习数据的紧凑、高效的表示，
we don't require any labels,
我们不需要任何标签，
this is completely unsupervised,
这完全是无监管的，
and so in this way,
所以，通过这种方式，
we're able to automatically encode information within the data itself
我们能够自动对数据本身中的信息进行编码，
to learn this latent space, autoencoding information, autoencoding data.
以了解这个隐空间，自编码信息，自编码数据。
Now, this is a pretty simple model,
这是一个非常简单的模型，
and it turns out that in practice, this idea of self encoding or autoencoding has a bit of a twist on it
事实证明，在实践中，自编码或自动编码的想法有一点扭曲，
to allow us to actually generate new examples,
使我们能够实际生成新的示例，
that are not only reconstructions of the input data itself.
这些示例不仅仅是输入数据本身的重建。
And this leads us to the concept of variational autoencoders or VAEs,
这就引出了变分自编码器的概念，或 VAE ，
with the traditional autoencoder that we just saw,
对于我们刚刚看到的传统自编码器，
if we pay closer attention to the latent layer,
如果我们更仔细地关注隐层，
which is shown in that orange salmon color,
它显示为橙色三文鱼色，
that latent layer is just a normal layer in the neural network,
这个隐层只是神经网络中的一个普通层，
it's completely deterministic,
这完全是决定的，
what that means is once we've trained the network,
这意味着，一旦我们训练了网络，
once the weights are set,
一旦设置了权重，
anytime we pass a given input in
任何时候我们传递给定的输入，
and go back through the latent layer, decode back out,
并通过潜在层返回，解码返回，
we're going to get the same exact reconstruction,
我们将得到完全相同的重建，
the weights aren't changing,
权重没有改变，
it's deterministic.
这是确定性的。
In contrast,
相比之下，
variational autoencoders, VAEs introduce an element of randomness,
变分自编码器 VAE 引入了随机性的元素，
a probabilistic twist on this idea of autoencoding,
这是对自编码思想的概率扭曲，
what this will allow us to do is to actually generate new images, similar to or new data instances,
这将允许我们生成新图像或新数据实例，
that are similar to the input data,
与输入数据相似，
but not forced to be strict reconstructions.
但不强制进行严格重建的实例。
In practice, with a variational autoencoder,
在实践中，使用变分自编码器，
we've replaced that single deterministic layer with a random sampling operation,
我们用随机采样操作取代了单一确定层，
now, instead of learning just the latent variables directly themselves,
现在，我们不是直接学习隐变量本身，
for each latent variable, we define a mean and a standard deviation,
我们为每个隐变量定义平均值和标准差，
that captures a probability distribution over that latent variable.
以捕获隐变量的概率分布。
What we've done is,
我们所做的是，
we've gone from a single vector of latent variable z
我们已经从隐变量 z 的单一向量，
to a vector of means μ and a vector of standard deviations σ,
变成了均值 μ 的向量和标准差 σ 的向量，
that parameterize the probability distributions around those latent variables.
它将这些隐变量周围的概率分布参数化。
what this will allow us to do is
这将允许我们现在做的是，
now sample using this element of randomness, this element of probability,
使用这个随机性元素，这个概率元素进行采样，
to then obtain a probabilistic representation of the latent space itself.
然后获得隐空间本身的概率表示。
As you hopefully can tell, right,
希望你能看出来，
this is very, very, very similar to the autoencoder itself,
这与自编码器本身非常相似，
but we've just added this probabilistic twist,
但我们刚刚增加了这个概率扭曲，
where we can sample in that intermediate space
我们可以在中间空间采样，
to get these samples of latent variables.
得到这些隐变量的样本。
Okay, now, to get a little more into the depth of how this is actually learned,
好的，现在，为了更深入地了解这是如何学习的，
how this is actually trained,
这是如何训练的，
with defining the VAE,
有了定义 VAE ，
we've eliminated this deterministic nature
我们已经消除了这种确定性的性质，
to now have these encoders and decoders that are probabilistic,
现在这些编码器和解码器都是概率的，
the encoder is computing a probability distribution of the latent variable z,
编码器计算的隐变量 z 的概率分布，
given input data x,
给定输入数据 x ，
while the decoder is doing the inverse,
而解码器进行相反的操作，
trying to learn a probability distribution back in the input data space,
试图学习输入数据空间中的概率分布，
given the latent variables z,
给定隐变量 z ，
and we define separate sets of weights Φ and θ,
并且我们定义了单独的权重集合 Φ 和 θ ，
to define the network weights for the encoder and decoder components of the v.
以定义用于 v 的编码器和解码器组件的网络权重。
All right, so when we get now
好的，我们现在，
to how we actually optimize and learn the network weights in the VAE,
如何优化和学习 VAE 中的网络权重，
first step is to define a loss function, right,
第一步是定义损失函数，
that's the core element to training a neural network,
这是训练神经网络的核心要素，
our loss is going to be a function of the data and a function of the neural network weights,
我们的损失将是数据的函数和神经网络权重的函数，
just like before,
就像以前一样，
but we have these two components, these two terms that define our VAE loss,
但我们有这两个组成部分，两个条目定义了我们的 VAE 损失，
first, we see the reconstruction loss just like before,
首先，我们看到重建损失，像以前一样，
where the goal is to capture the difference between our input data and the reconstructed output,
目标是捕捉我们的输入数据和重建输出之间的差异，
and now for the VAE, we've introduced a second term to the loss,
现在对于 VAE ，我们引入了损失的第二个项，
what we call the regularization term,
我们称之为正则化项，
often, you'll maybe even see this referred to as a VAE loss
通常，你甚至可能会看到这被称为 VAE 损失，
and we'll go into, we'll go into describing what this regularization term means and what it's doing.
我们将进入描述这个正则化术语的含义和它在做什么。
To do that and to understand, remember and, and keep in mind,
要做到这一点，并理解，记住，
that in all neural network operations,
在所有神经网络操作中，
our goal is to try to optimize the network weights
我们的目标是尝试优化网络权重，
with respect to the data, with respect to minimizing this objective loss,
相对于数据，从而将这种客观损失降至最低，
and so here we're concerned with the network weights Φ and θ,
所以这里我们关注的是网络权重 Φ 和 θ ，
that define the weights of the encoder and the decoder.
它们定义了编码器和解码器的权重。
We consider these two terms,
我们考虑这两个项目，
first, the reconstruction loss,
首先是重建损失，
again the reconstruction loss is very, very similar, same as before,
再次，重建损失非常相似，和以前一样，
you can think of it as the error or the likelihood,
你可以认为它是误差或可能性，
that effectively captures the difference between your input and your outputs,
有效地捕捉到你的输入和输出之间的差异，
and again, we can train this in an unsupervised way,
同样，我们可以以一种无监督的方式进行训练，
not requiring any labels to force the latent space and the network
不需要任何标签来迫使隐空间和网络
to learn how to effectively reconstruct the input data.
学习如何有效地重建输入数据。
The second term, the regularization term,
第二个条目，正规化条目，
is now where things get a bit more interesting,
现在是事情变得更有趣的地方，
so let's go on into this in a little bit more detail.
所以，让我们更详细地讨论这个问题。
Because we have this probability distribution
因为我们有这个概率分布，
and we're trying to compute this encoding and then decode back up,
我们试图计算这个编码，然后再解码回来，
as part of regularizing,
作为正规化的一部分，
we want to take that inference over the latent distribution
我们希望对隐分布采取这种推断，
and constrain it to behave nicely, if you will,
并约束它表现良好，如果你愿意的话，
the way we do that is
我们这样做的方法是，
we place what we call a prior on the latent distribution,
我们把我们所说的先验放在隐分布上，
and what this is is some initial hypothesis or guess about what that latent variable space may look like,
这是一些关于隐变量空间可能是什么样子的初始假设或猜测，
this helps us and helps the network to enforce a latent space
这有助于我们和网络实施一个隐空间，
that roughly tries to follow this prior distribution,
尝试遵循这种先前的分布，
and this prior is denoted as p of z, right,
这个先验信息表示为 p(z) ，
that term D, that's effectively the regularization term,
那项 D ，就是正则化项，
it's capturing a distance between our encoding of the latent variables
它捕捉到了我们对隐变量的编码
and our prior hypothesis about what the structure of that latent space should look like,
和我们先前关于隐空间结构应该是什么样子的假设之间的距离，
so over the course of training,
所以，在训练过程中，
we're trying to enforce that,
我们努力执行这一点，
each of those latent variables adapts a, adapts a probability distribution that's similar to that prior.
这些隐变量中的每一个都适应一个类似于先验的概率分布。
A common choice when training VAEs and developing these models is
在训练 VAE 和开发这些模型时，一个常见的选择是，
to enforce the latent variables to be roughly standard normal gouging distributions,
将隐变量强制为大致标准的正态分布，
meaning that they are centered around mean zero
这意味着它们以均值零为中心，
and they have a standard deviation of one,
并且它们的标准差为一，
what this allows us to do is
这让我们能够做的是，
to encourage the encoder to put the latent variables roughly around a centered space,
鼓励编码者将隐变量大致放在一个中心空间周围，
distributing the encoding smoothly,
平稳地分布编码，
so that we don't get too much divergence away from that smooth space,
这样我们就不会从这个平滑的空间中得到太多的偏离，
which can occur if the network tries to cheat and try to simply memorize the data,
如果网络试图作弊并试图简单地记住数据，就会发生这种情况，
by placing the gaussian standard normal prior on the latent space,
通过将高斯标准正态先验放在隐空间上，
we can define a concrete mathematical term,
我们可以定义一个具体的数学术语，
that captures the distance the divergence between our encoded latent variables and this prior,
捕捉编码的隐变量与该先验之间的距离，
and this is called the KL divergence,
这称为 KL 散度，
when our prior is a standard normal,
当我们的前项是标准正态时，
the KL divergence takes the form of the equation that I'm showing up on the screen,
KL 散度采用我在屏幕上显示的方程的形式，
but what I want you to really get away come away with is that,
但我想让你们真正[逃脱]的是，
the concept of trying to smooth things out and to capture this divergence
试着让事情变得平滑，捕捉这种差异的概念，
and this difference between the prior and the latent encoding,
以及先验编码和隐编码之间的差异，
is all this kl term is trying to capture.
这就是 KL 术语试图捕捉的全部。
So it's a bit of math, and I I acknowledge that,
所以这有点数学，我承认这一点，
but what I want to next go into is
但我接下来想要探讨的是，
really what is the intuition behind this regularization operation,
这个正规化操作背后的直觉是什么，
why do we do this
我们为什么要这样做，
and why does the normal prior, in particular, work effectively for VAEs.
为什么正常的先验，特别是对 VAE 。
So let's consider what properties we want our latent space to adopt
所以，让我们考虑我们希望隐空间采用什么性质，
and for this regularization to achieve,
以及为了实现这种正规化，
the first is this goal of continuity,
首先是这个连续性的目标，
we don't what we mean by continuity is that,
我们没有，我们所说的连续性的意思是，
if there are points in the latent space that are close together,
如果在隐空间中有一些点很接近，
ideally after decoding,
理想情况下是在解码之后，
we should recover two reconstructions that are similar in content,
我们应该恢复两个内容相似的重建，
that make sense that they're close together.
这有意义的，它们离得很近。
The second key property is this idea of completeness,
第二个关键属性是这种完整性的概念，
we don't want there to be gaps in the latent space,
我们不希望在隐空间中有空隙，
we want to be able to decode and sample from the latent space
我们希望能够从隐空间解码和采样，
in a way that is smooth and a way that is connected.
以一种流畅和连接的方式。
To get more concrete,
更具体地说，
let's ask what could be the consequences of not regularizing our latent space at all,
让我们问一问，如果根本不把我们的隐空间正规化，会有什么后果，
well, if we don't regularize,
如果我们不正规化，
we can end up with instances,
我们可能会得到这样的例子，
where there are points that are close in the latent space,
在隐空间中有一些接近的点，
but don't end up with similar decodings or similar reconstructions,
但最终不会得到类似的解码或类似的重建，
similarly, we could have points that don't lead to meaningful reconstructions at all,
同样，我们可能会有一些根本不会导致有意义的重建的点，
they're somehow encoded,
它们不知何故被编码了，
but we can't decode effectively.
但我们无法有效地解码。
Regularization allows us to realize points that end up close into latent space
正规化使我们能够认识到最终接近隐空间的点，
and also are similarly reconstructed and meaningfully reconstructed.
也可以进行类似的重建和有意义的重建。
Okay, so continuing with this example,
好的，继续这个例子，
the example that I showed there and I didn't get into details,
我在那里展示的例子，我没有深入到细节，
was showing these shapes, these shapes of different colors
展示了这些形状，这些不同颜色的形状，
and that were trying to be encoded in some lower dimensional space,
试图在一些低维空间中编码，
with regularization,
有了正规化，
we are able to achieve this by trying to minimize that regularization term,
我们能够通过尝试最小化正则化项来实现这一点，
it's not sufficient to just employ the reconstruction loss alone to achieve this continuity and this completeness,
仅仅利用重建损失来实现这种连续性和完整性是不够的，
because of the fact that without regularization,
因为没有正规化，
just encoding and reconstructing does not guarantee the properties of continuity and completeness,
仅仅编码和重构并不能保证连续性和完备性，
we overcome this,
我们克服了这一点，
these issues of having potentially pointed distributions, having discontinuities, having disparate means,
这些问题具有潜在的指向性分布，具有不连续，具有不同的平均值，
that could end up in the latent space without the effect of regularization,
最终可能在没有正则化影响的隐空间中结束，
we overcome this,
我们克服这个，
by now regularizing the mean and the variance of the encoded latent distributions according to that normal prior,
根据正态先验正则化编码的潜在分布的均值和方差，
what this allows is for the learned distributions of those latent variables to effectively overlap in the latent space,
这使得学习到的那些隐变量的分布在隐空间中有效地重叠，
because everything is regularized to have, according to this prior, of mean zero, standard deviation one,
因为根据这个先验，所有的东西都被规则化为平均为零，标准差为一，
and that centers the means,
这使平均值居中，
regularizes the variances for each of those independent latent variable distributions.
使每个独立隐变量分布的方差正则化。
Together, the effect of this regularization in net is that
总而言之，这种正则化在网络中的效果是，
we can achieve continuity and completeness in the latent space,
我们可以在隐空间中实现连续性和完备性，
points and distances that are close should correspond to similar reconstructions that we get out.
接近的点和距离应该与我们得到的类似重建相对应。
So hopefully this gets at some of the intuition
所以希望这能得到一些直觉，
behind the idea of the VAE, behind the idea of the regularization
在 VAE 后的思想，正则化的思想，
and trying to enforce the structured normal prior on the latent space.
并试图在隐空间上强制结构化的正态先验。
With this in hand,
有了这一点，
with the two components of our loss function
随着我们损失函数的两个组件，
reconstructing the inputs, regularizing learning to try to achieve continuity and completeness,
重建输入正规化，学习以尝试实现连续性和完整性，
we can now think about how we define a forward pass through the network,
我们现在可以考虑如何定义通过网络的前向传递，
going from an input example
从输入示例开始，
and being able to decode and sample from the latent variables to look at new examples.
并能够从潜在变量解码和采样以查看新示例。
Our last critical step is
我们的最后一个关键步骤是
how the actual back propagation training algorithm is defined and how we achieve this,
如何定义实际的反向传播训练算法，以及如何实现这一点，
the key, as I introduce with VAEs, is this notion of randomness of sampling
正如我在 VAE 中介绍的那样，关键是抽样随机性，
that we have introduced by defining these probability distributions over each of the latent variables,
我们通过定义每个隐变量的概率分布而引入的，
the problem this gives us is that,
这给我们带来的问题是，
we cannot back propagate directly through anything that has an element of sampling,
我们不能直接通过任何含有抽样元素的东西来反向传播，
anything that has an element of randomness,
任何带有随机元素的东西，
back propagation requires completely deterministic nodes, deterministic layers
反向传播要求完全确定的节点，确定的层，
to be able to successfully apply gradient descent and the back propagation algorithm.
能够成功地应用梯度下降和反向传播算法。
The breakthrough idea that enabled VAE to be trained completely end to end was
使 VAE 能够被完全端到端训练的突破性想法是
this idea of reparameterization within that sampling layer,
这个在采样层内重新参数化的想法，
and I'll give you the key idea about how this operation works,
我会给你关于这个操作如何运作的关键想法，
it's actually really quite level, quite clever.
它是相当聪明的，
So, as I said, when we have a notion of randomness of probability,
所以，就像我说的，当我们有了概率的随机性概念时，
we can't sample directly through that layer,
我们不能直接通过这一层进行采样，
instead, with reparameterization,
取而代之的是，利用重新参数化，
what we do is we redefine how a latent variable vector is sampled,
我们所做的是重新定义如何对隐变量向量进行采样，
as a sum of a fixed deterministic mean μ,
作为固定的确定性平均值 μ ，
a fixed vector of standard deviation σ,
和固定的标准偏差 σ 的向量，
and now the trick is that we divert all the randomness, all the sampling to a random constant ε,
现在的诀窍是我们把所有的随机性，所有的抽样，都转移到一个随机常数 ε 上，
that's drawn from a normal distribution,
它是从正态分布中提取出来的，
so mean itself is fixed,
所以平均值本身是固定的，
standard deviation is fixed,
标准差也是固定的，
all the randomness and the sampling occurs according to that ε constant,
所有的随机性和抽样都是根据这个 ε 常数进行的，
we can then scale the mean and standard deviation by that random constant
然后，我们可以通过该随机常数来调整平均值和标准差，
to re-achieve the sampling operation within the latent variables themselves.
以重新实现隐变量本身内的采样操作。
What this actually looks like,
这是什么样子的，
and an illustration that breaks down this concept of reparameterization and divergence, is as follows.
一个打破这种再参数化和发散概念的插图，如下所示。
So looking, looking here, right,
所以看这里，
what I've shown is,
我展示的是，
these completely deterministic steps in blue and the sampling random steps in orange,
蓝色的完全确定的步骤和橙色的采样随机步骤，
originally, if our latent variables are what effectively are capturing the randomness, the sampling themselves,
如果我们的隐变量是有效地捕捉随机性的东西，样本本身，
we have this problem,
我们就有这个问题，
in that we can't back propagate,
因为我们不能反向传播，
we can't train directly through anything that has stochasticity that has randomness,
我们不能直接通过任何具有随机性的东西进行训练，
what reparameterization allows us to do is,
重新参数化允许我们做的是，
it shifts this diagram,
它移动了这张图，
where now we've completely diverted that sampling operation off to the side,
现在我们已经完全将采样操作转移到一边，
to this constant ε,
到这个常数 ε ，
which is drawn from a normal prior,
它是从正常的先验绘制的，
and now when we look back at our latent variable,
现在当我们回过头来看我们的隐变量，
it is deterministic with respect to that sampling operation,
它是关于采样操作的确定性的，
what this means is that,
这意味着，
we can back propagate to update our network weights completely end to end,
我们可以完全端到端地反向传播来更新我们的网络权重，
without having to worry about direct randomness, direct stochasticity within those latent variables z,
而不必担心那些隐变量 z 内的直接随机性，
this trick is really, really powerful,
这个技巧非常强大，
because it enabled the ability to train these VAEs completely end to end in through back propagation algorithm.
因为它能够通过反向传播算法完全端到端地训练这些 VAEs 。
Alright, so at this point, we've gone through the core architecture of VAEs,
好的，至此，我们已经了解了 VAE 的核心架构，
we've introduced these two terms of the loss,
我们已经介绍了这两个项目的损失，
we've seen how we can train it end to end.
我们已经看到了如何对其进行端到端的训练。
Now, let's consider what these latent variables are actually capturing
现在，让我们考虑一下这些隐变量实际上捕捉到了什么，
and what they represent,
以及它们代表了什么，
when we impose this distributional prior,
当我们施加这种分布先验时，
what it allows us to do is to sample effectively from the latent space
它允许我们做的是从隐空间有效地采样，
and actually slowly perturb the value of single latent variables,
慢慢地扰动单个隐变量的值，
keeping the other ones fixed,
保持其他变量不变，
and what you can observe,
你可以观察到的，
and what you can see here is that
你可以在这里看到的是，
by doing that perturbation that tuning of the value of the latent variables,
通过扰动，调整隐变量的值，
we can run the decoder of the VAE every time,
我们可以每次运行 VAE 的解码器，
reconstruct the output every time we do that tuning,
每次进行调整时重建输出，
and what you'll see hopefully with this example with the face is that,
在这个脸部的例子中，你会看到的是，
an individual latent variable is capturing something semantically informative, something meaningful,
一个单独的隐变量捕捉到了一些语义上的信息，一些有意义的东西，
and we see that by this perturbation, by this tuning,
我们看到通过这个扰动，通过这个调整，
in this example, the face, as you hopefully can appreciate, is shifting,
在这个例子中，希望你能欣赏到这一点，面部正在改变，
the pose is shifting,
姿势在改变，
and all this is driven by is the perturbation of a single latent variable,
所有这一切都是由单一隐变量的扰动驱动的，
tuning the value of that latent variable
调整隐变量的值，
and seeing how that affects the decoded reconstruction.
看看这对解码后的重建有什么影响。
The network is actually able to learn these different encoded features, these different latent variables,
网络实际上能够学习这些不同的编码特征，这些不同的隐变量，
such that by perturbing the values of them individually,
这样通过分别扰动它们的值，
we can interpret and make sense of what those latent variables mean and what they represent.
我们可以理解这些隐变量的含义和它们所代表的意义。
To make this more concrete,
为了更具体，
we can consider even multiple latent variables simultaneously,
我们甚至可以同时考虑多个隐变量，
compare one against the other,
将一个与另一个进行比较，
and ideally, we want those latent features to be as independent as possible
理想情况下，我们希望这些隐特征尽可能独立，
in order to get at the most compact and richest representation and compact encoding.
以便获得最紧凑、最丰富的表示和紧凑编码。
So here again, in this example of faces,
所以这里，在这个人脸的例子中，
we're walking along two axis,
我们沿着两个轴行走，
head pose on the x axis
头部姿势在 x 轴上，
and what appears to be kind of a notion of a smile on the y axis.
看起来像是微笑的概念在 y 轴上。
And you can see that,
你可以看到，
with these reconstructions,
通过这些重建，
we can actually perturb these features
我们可以扰乱这些特征，
to be able to perturb the end effect in the reconstructed space.
从而能够扰乱重建空间中的末端效应。
And so ultimately, with with VAE,
所以，最终，对于 VAV ，
our goal is to try to enforce as much information to be captured in that encoding as possible,
我们的目标是尝试强制执行尽可能多的信息，以便在该编码中捕获，
we want these latent features to be independent and ideally disentangled.
我们希望这些隐特征是独立的，理想情况下是分开的。
it turns out that there is a very clever and simple way
事实证明，有一种非常聪明和简单的方法，
to try to encourage this independence and this disentanglement,
来鼓励这种独立和这种分开，
while this may look a little complicated with the math and a bit scary,
虽然这在数学上可能看起来有点复杂，有点可怕，
I will break this down
但我将分解这个，
with the idea of how a very simple concept enforces this independent latent encoding and this disentanglement.
使用一个非常简单的概念如何实施这种独立的隐编码和这种解耦的想法。
All this term is showing is those two components of the loss,
所有这一项都是损失的两个组成部分，
the reconstruction term, the regularization term,
重建项，正则化项，
that's what I want you to focus on.
这就是我想要你关注的。
The idea of latent space disentanglement really arose with this concept of β β-VAEs,
隐空间解耦的想法是从 β-VAE 的这个概念中产生的，
what β-VAEs do is,
β-VAE 所做的是，
they introduce this parameter β
引入这个参数 β ，
and what it is it's awaiting constant,
它是等待常数，
the awaiting constant controls, how powerful that regularization term is in the overall loss of the VAE,
等待常数控制正则化项在 VAE 的总体损失中有多强大，
and it turns out that by increasing the value of β,
事实证明，通过增加 β 的值，
you can try to encourage greater disentanglement, more efficient encoding
你可以尝试鼓励更大的解耦，更有效的编码，
to enforce these latent variables to be uncorrelated with each other.
以强制这些隐变量彼此不相关。
Now, if you're interested in mathematically why β-VAEs enforce this disentanglement,
现在，如果你对数学上为什么 β-VAE 强制这种解耦感兴趣，
there are many papers in the literature and proofs
有很多文献和证明，
and discussions as to why this occurs,
以及关于为什么会发生这种情况的讨论，
and we can point you in those directions,
我们可以向你指出这些方向，
but to get a sense of what this actually affects downstream,
但为了了解这会对下游产生什么影响，
when we look at face reconstruction as a task of interest
当我们将人脸重建视为一项感兴趣的任务时，
with a standard VAE, no β term, or rather a β of one,
我们使用标准的 VAE ，没有 β 项，或者更确切地说， β 项为 1 ，
you can hopefully appreciate that,
希望你能理解，
the features of the rotation of the head,
头部的旋转，
the pose and the rotation of the head
姿势和头部的旋转，
is also actually ends up being correlated with smile and the facial, the mouth expression in the mouth position,
也与微笑和面部，嘴部的表情相关，
in that as the head pose is changing,
因为，随着头部姿势的改变，
the apparent smile or the position of the mouth is also changing,
明显的微笑或嘴巴的位置也在改变，
but with β-VAEs, empirically we can observe that,
但通过 β-VAE ，我们可以观察到，
with imposing these β values much, much, much greater than one,
通过施加比 1 大得多的 β 值，
we can try to enforce greater disentanglement,
我们可以尝试实施更大的解耦，
where now we can consider only a single latent variable head pose
现在我们只能考虑一个隐变量头部姿势，
and the smile, the position of the mouth in these images is more constant
这些图像中的微笑和嘴巴的位置更恒定，
compared to the standard VAE.
与标准的的 VAE 相比。
Alright, so this is really all the core math, the core operations,
好的，这就是所有的核心数学，核心运算，
the core architecture of the VAE,
VAE 的核心架构，
that we're going to cover in today's lecture and in this class in general.
我们将在今天的课程中讨论。
To close this section, and as a final note,
在这节课结束之前。作为最后一个注解，
I want to remind you back to the motivating example,
我想提醒大家回到鼓舞人心的例子，
that I introduced at the beginning of this lecture, facial detection.
我在本课开始时介绍的，面部检测。
Where now hopefully you've understood this concept of latent variable learning and encoding,
现在，希望你已经理解了隐变量学习和编码的概念，
and how this may be useful for a task like facial detection,
以及这对于面部检测这样的任务是多么有用，
where we may want to learn those distributions of the underlying features in the data,
我们可能想要了解数据中隐特征的分布，
and indeed, you're going to get hands on practice in the software labs
实际上，你将在软件实验中亲身实践，
to build variational autoencoders,
建立变化自编码器，
that can automatically uncover features underlying facial detection data sets
可以自动发现面部检测数据集的隐特征，
and use this to actually understand underlying and hidden biases,
并使用这一点来了解潜在和隐藏的偏见，
that may exist with those data and with those models.
可能来自这些数据和模型。
And it doesn't just stop there,
而且它并不只是止步于此，
tomorrow we'll have a very, very exciting guest lecture
明天我们将有一个非常令人兴奋的客座讲座，
on robust and trustworthy deep learning,
关于稳健和值得信赖的深度学习，
which will take this concept a step further
它将使这个概念更进一步，
to realize how we can use this idea of generative models and latent variable learning
认识到我们如何使用生成模型和隐变量学习的想法，
to not only uncover and diagnose biases,
不仅发现和诊断偏见，
but actually solve and mitigate some of those harmful effects of those biases
而且实际上解决和减轻这些偏见的一些有害影响，
in neural networks for facial detection and other applications.
在用于面部检测和其他应用的神经网络中。
Alright, so to summarize quickly the key points of VAEs,
好的，简单总结一下 VAE 的要点，
we've gone through how they're able to compress data into this compact encoded representation,
我们已经了解了它们是如何将数据压缩到这个紧凑的编码表示中的，
from this representation,
从这个表示中，
we can generate reconstructions of the input in a completely unsupervised fashion,
我们可以以完全无监督的方式生成输入的重构，
we can train them end to end using the reparameterization trick,
我们可以使用重新参数化技巧对它们进行端到端的训练，
we can understand the semantic interpretation of individual latent variables by perturbing their values,
我们可以通过扰动个体隐变量的值来理解它们的语义解释，
and finally, we can sample from the latent space
最后，我们可以从潜在空间中进行采样，
to generate new examples by passing back up through the decoder.
通过解码器向上传递来生成新的示例。
So VAE are looking at this idea of latent variable encoding and density estimation as their core problem,
所以 VAE 把隐变量编码和密度估计作为他们的核心问题，
what if now we only focus on the quality of the generated samples,
如果现在我们只关注生成样本的质量，
and that's the task that we care more about.
这是我们更关心的任务。
For that, we're going to transition to a new type of generative model
所以，我们将过渡到一种新型的生成性模型，
called a generative adversarial network or GAN,
称为生成性对抗网络，或称 GAN ，
where with GANs, our goal is really that,
对于 GAN，我们的目标是，
we care more about how well we generate new instances that are similar to the existing data,
更多地关心如何生成与现有数据相似的新实例，
meaning that we want to try to sample from a potentially very complex distribution,
这意味着我们希望尝试从潜在非常复杂的分布中进行采样，
that the model is trying to approximate,
模型试图近似的（分布），
it can be extremely, extremely difficult to learn that distribution directly,
直接学习这种分布可能非常困难，
because it's complex, it's high dimensional
因为它很复杂，维度很高，
and we want to be able to get around that complexity,
我们希望能够绕过这种复杂性，
what GANs do is they say,
GAN 所做的是，他们会说，
okay, what if we start from something super, super simple,
好的，如果我们从超级简单的东西开始，
as simple as it can get completely random noise,
就像它可以得到完全随机的噪音一样简单，
could we build a neural network architecture,
我们能否建立一种神经网络体系结构，
that can learn to generate synthetic examples from complete random noise.
能够学习从完全随机的噪音中生成合成样本。
And this is the underlying concept of GANs,
这就是 GAN 的基本概念，
where the goal is to train this generator network,
目标是训练这个生成器网络，
that learns a transformation from noise to the training data distribution,
学习从噪声到训练数据分布的转换，
with the goal of making the generated examples as close to the real [] as possible.
目标是使生成的示例尽可能接近真实的[] 。
With GANs, the breakthrough idea here was
对于 GAN ，这里的突破性想法是，
to interface these two neural networks together,
将这两个神经网络连接在一起，
one being a generator and one being a discriminator,
一个是生成器，一个是判别器，
and these two components, the generator and discriminator,
而这两个组成部分，生成器和判别器，
are at war, at competition with each other,
处于战争之中，相互竞争，
specifically, the goal of the generator network is
具体地说，生成器网络的目标是，
to look at random noise
观察随机噪声，
and try to produce an imitation of the data that's as close to real as possible,
并试图产生尽可能接近真实数据的模拟数据，
the discriminator then takes the output of the generator as well as some real data examples,
然后，判别器获取生成器的输出以及一些真实的数据示例，
and tries to learn a classification decision,
并尝试学习分类决策，
distinguishing real from fake,
辨别真假，
and effectively in the GAN,
在 GAN 中，
these two components are going back and forth, competing each other,
这两个部分相互竞争，
trying to force the discriminator to better learn this distinction between real and fake,
试图迫使判别器更好地区分真假，
while the generator is trying to fool and outperform the ability of the discriminator to make that classification.
而生成器试图愚弄和超越判别器进行分类的能力。
So that's the overlying concept,
所以这就是最重要的概念，
but what I'm really excited about is the next example,
但真正让我兴奋的是下一个例子，
which is one of my absolute favorite illustrations and walkthroughs in this class,
这是我在这门课上最喜欢的插图和演练之一，
and it gets at the intuition behind GANs,
它得到了 GAN 背后的直觉，
how they work and the underlying concept.
它们是如何工作的，以及潜在的概念。
Okay, we're going to look at a 1D example,
我们来看一个一维例子，
points on a line, right,
直线上的点，
that's the data that we're working with,
这就是我们处理的数据，
and again, the generator starts from random noise,
同样，生成器从随机噪声开始，
produces some fake data,
产生一些虚假数据，
they're going to fall somewhere on this one dimensional line.
它们会落在这条一维线上的某个地方。
Now the next step is the discriminator then sees these points,
现在下一步是判别器看到这些点，
and it also sees some real data,
它还看到了一些真实的数据，
the goal of the discriminator is to be trained to output a probability,
判别器的目标是训练它输出概率，
that an instance it sees is real or fake.
它所看到的实例是真的还是假的。
And initially, in the beginning before training,
最初，在训练之前，
it's not trained, right,
它没有得到训练，
so its predictions may not be very good,
所以，它的预测可能不是很好，
but over the course of training,
但在训练的过程中，
you're going to train it
你将训练它，
and it hopefully will start increasing the probability for those examples that are real
它有望开始增加那些真实例子的概率，
and decreasing the probability for those examples that are fake,
减少那些虚假例子的可能性，
overall goal is to predict what is real,
总体目标是预测什么是真实的，
until eventually the discriminator reaches this point,
直到最终判别器达到这一点，
where it has a perfect separation, perfect classification of real versus fake.
它有一个完美的分离，完美的真假分类。
Okay, so at this point, the discriminator thinks,
好的，在这一点上，判别器认为，
okay, I've done my job,
好的，我已经完成了我的工作，
now we go back to the generator
现在我们回到生成器，
and it sees the examples of where the real data lie,
它会看到真实数据所在的示例，
and it can be forced to start moving its generated fake data
而且，它可能会被迫开始将其生成的虚假数据，
closer and closer, increasingly closer to the real data,
越来越接近真实数据，
we can then go back to the discriminator,
然后我们可以回到判别器，
which receives these newly synthesized examples from the generator,
它从生成器接收这些新合成的示例，
and repeats that same process of estimating the probability that any given point is real,
并重复相同的过程来估计任何给定点为真实的概率，
and learning to increase the probability of the true real examples,
学习增加真实例的概率，
decrease the probability of the fake points,
减少假点的概率，
adjusting, adjusting over the course of its training.
适应在它的训练过程中。
And finally, we can go back and repeat to the generator again one last time,
最后，我们可以回到生成器上，最后一次重复，
the generator starts moving those fake points closer, closer and closer to the real data,
生成器开始将这些假点移动得越来越接近真实数据，
such that the fake data is almost following the distribution of the real data.
以至于假数据几乎都在跟随真实数据的分布。
At this point, it becomes very, very hard for the discriminator to distinguish
在这一点上，判别器很难区分，
between what is real and what is fake,
什么是真的，什么是假的，
while the generator will continue to try to create fake data points to fool the discriminator,
生成器将继续尝试创建虚假数据点来愚弄判别器，
this is really the key concept,
这确实是关键概念，
the underlying intuition behind how the components of the GAN are essentially competing with each other,
GAN 组件如何本质上相互竞争的基本直觉，
going back and forth between the generator and the discriminator,
在生成器和判别器之间来回移动，
and in fact, this is this intuitive concept is how the GAN is trained in practice,
事实上，这就是 GAN 是如何在实践中被训练的直观概念，
where the generator first tries to synthesize new examples,
生成器首先试图合成新的例子，
synthetic examples to fool the discriminator,
合成例子来愚弄判别器，
and the goal of the discriminator is to take both the fake examples and the real data
而判别器的目标是同时获取虚假实例和真实数据，
to try to identify the synthesized instances.
以尝试识别合成实例。
In training, what this means is that the objective,
在训练中，这意味着目标是，
the loss for the generator and discriminator have to be at odds with each other,
生成器和判别器的损失必须是彼此不一致的，
they're adversarial,
它们是对抗性的，
and that is what gives rise to the component of adversarial in generative adversarial network,
这就是生成对抗性网络中对抗性成分的原因，
these adversarial objectives are then put together
然后将这些对抗性目标放在一起，
to then define what it means to arrive at a stable global optimum,
以定义达到稳定的全局最优意味着什么，
where the generator is capable of producing the true data distribution,
在这种情况下，生成器能够产生真实数据分布，
that would completely fool the discriminator,
将会完全欺骗判别器，
concretely, this can be defined mathematically in terms of a loss objective
具体地说，这可以在数学上定义为损失目标，
and again though I'm, I'm showing math,
再次，虽然我在展示数学，
I can, we can distill this down
我们可以把这些提炼出来，
and go through what each of these terms reflect in terms of that core intuitive idea and conceptual idea,
通过每个术语所反映的核心直观概念和概念概念，
that hopefully that 1D example conveyed.
希望这个一维例子能传达出来。
So we'll first consider the perspective of the discriminator D,
所以我们首先考虑判别者的观点 D ，
its goal is to maximize probability that its decisions,
它的目标是最大化它的决定的概率，
in its decisions,
在它的决定中，
that real data are classified real, fake data classified as fake,
真实的数据被归类为真实的，假数据被归类为假的，
so here the first term G(z) is the generator's output,
所以，这里的第一项 G(z) 是生成器的输出，
and D(G(z)) is the discriminator's estimate of that generated output as being fake,
D(G(z)) 是判别器对生成器的输出为假的估计，
D(x), x is the real data,
D(x) ， x 是真实的数据，
and so D(x) is the estimate of the probability that a real instance is fake,
所以 D(x) 是真实实例为假的概率的估计，
1-D(x) is the estimate that that real instance is real,
1-D(x) 是真实实例是真实的估计，
so here in both these cases,
因此，在这两种情况下，
the discriminator is producing a decision about fake data, real data,
判别器都在做出关于虚假数据和真实数据的决定，
and together it wants to try to maximize the probability that it's getting answers correct, right.
它想要一起努力最大化它得到正确答案的可能性。
Now with the generator, we have those same exact terms,
现在，对于生成器，我们有相同的条目，
but keep in mind the generator is never able to affect
但请记住，生成器永远不能影响，
anything that the discriminator decision is actually doing,
判别器决策做的任何事情，
besides generating new data examples.
除了生成新的数据示例之外。
So for the generator, its objective is simply
因此，对于生成器来说，其目标只是，
to minimize the probability that the generated data is identified as fake.
将生成的数据被识别为虚假数据的概率降至最低。
Together, we want to then put this together
总之，我们想把这些放在一起，
to define what it means for the generator to synthesize fake images
定义生成器合成假图像意味着什么，
that hopefully fool the discriminator.
希望能愚弄判别者。
All in all, right, this term,
总而言之，这个项目，
besides the math, besides the particularities of this definition,
除了数学，除了这个定义的特殊性，
what I want you to get away from this, from this section on GANs,
我想让你们从这个关于 GAN 的这一节中得到的，
is that we have this dual competing objective,
是我们有这个双重竞争的目标，
where the generator is trying to synthesize these synthetic examples,
生成器试图合成这些合成例子，
that ideally fool the best discriminator possible,
尽可能地愚弄最好的判别者，
and in doing so, the goal is to build up a network,
在这样做的过程中，目标是建立一个网络，
via this adversarial training, this adversarial competition
通过这种对抗性训练，这种对抗性竞争，
to use the generator to create new data,
使用生成器来创建新数据，
that best mimics the true data distribution and its completely synthetic new instances.
最能模拟真实数据分布及其完全合成的新实例。
What this amounts to in practice is that after the training process,
实际上，在培训过程之后，
you can look exclusively at the generator component
你可以只查看生成器组件，
and use it to then create new data instances.
然后使用它来创建新的数据实例。
All this is done by starting from random noise
所有这些都是从随机噪声开始，
and trying to learn a model that goes from random noise to the real data distribution.
并试图学习从随机噪声到真实数据分布的模型。
And effectively what gans are doing is learning a function,
实际上， GAN 在做的是学习一种函数，
that transforms that distribution of random noise to some target,
将随机噪声的分布转化为某个目标，
what this mapping does is,
这种映射的作用是，
it allows us to take a particular observation of noise in that noise space
它允许我们对噪声空间中的噪声进行特定的观察，
and map it to some output, a particular output in our target data space,
并将其映射到某些输出，目标数据空间中的特定输出，
and in turn, if we consider some other random sample of noise,
反过来，如果我们考虑一些其他随机的噪声样本，
if we feed it through the generator of GAN,
如果我们把它送入 GAN 的生成器，
it's going to produce a completely new instance,
它将产生一个全新的实例，
falling somewhere else on that true data distribution manifold,
落在真正的数据分布流形上的其他地方，
and indeed, what we can actually do is
事实上，我们实际上可以做的是，
interpolate and traverse between trajectories in the noise space,
在噪声空间中的轨迹之间进行内插和遍历，
that then map to traversals and interpolations in the target data space,
然后映射到目标数据空间中的遍历和内插，
and this is really, really cool,
这真的很酷，
because now you can think about an initial point and a target point
因为现在你可以考虑一个起始点和一个目标点，
and all the steps that are going to take you
所以步骤将会让你，
to synthesize and go between those images in that target data distribution.
在目标数据分布中合成和处理这些图像。
So hopefully this gives a sense of this concept of generative modeling for the purpose of creating new data instances.
希望这能让我们对用于创建新数据实例的生成性建模的概念有一个了解。
And that notion of interpolation and data transformation
而这种插补和数据转换的概念
leads very nicely to some of the recent advances and applications of GANs,
很好地引领了 GAN 最近的一些进步和应用，
where one particularly commonly employed idea is
其中一个特别常用的想法是，
to try to iteratively grow the GANs to get more and more detailed image generations,
尝试再次迭代 GAN 以获得更多更详细的图像生成，
progressively adding layers over the course of training
在训练过程中逐步添加层，
to then refine the examples generated by the generator.
然后改进由生成器生成的示例。
And this is the approach that was used to generate those synthetic, those images of those synthetic faces,
这就是用来生成那些合成脸部的图像的方法，
that I showed at the beginning of this lecture,
我在这节课的开头展示的图像，
this idea of using GAN that is refined iteratively to produce higher resolution images.
使用迭代细化的 GAN 来产生更高分辨率的图像。
Another way we can extend this concept is
我们可以扩展这一概念的另一种方法是，
to extend the GAN architecture to consider particular tasks
扩展 GAN 架构以考虑特定任务，
and impose further structure on the network itself,
并将进一步的结构强加于网络本身，
one particular idea is to say,
一个特别的想法是，
okay, what if we have a particular label or some factor,
好的，如果我们有一个特定的标签或一些因素，
that we want to condition the generation on,
我们想要以此为条件来产生，
we call the c
我们称为 c ，
and it supplied to both the generator and the discriminator,
它同时提供给生成器和判别器，
what this will allow us to achieve is paired translation between different types of data,
这将使我们能够实现不同类型数据之间的配对转换，
so, for example, we can have images of a street view
例如，我们可以有街景的图像，
and we can have images of the segmentation of that street view
我们可以有街景的分割图像，
and we can build again that can directly translate between the street view and the segmentation.
我们可以重新构建可以在街景图像和分割之间直接转换。
Let's make this more concrete by considering some particular examples,
让我们通过考虑一些特定的例子来使这一点更加具体，
so what I just described was going from a segmentation label to a street scene,
所以我刚才描述的就是从一个分割标签变成一个街头场景，
we can also translate between a satellite view, aerial satellite image
我们还可以将卫星视图，航空卫星图像转换为
to what is the roadmap equivalent of that aerial satellite image
相当于该航空卫星图像的路线图，
or a particular annotation or labels of the image of a building
或将建筑物图像的特定注释或标签转换为
to the actual visual realization and visual facade of that building,
建筑物的实际视觉实现和视觉立面，
we can translate between different lighting conditions, day to night,
我们可以在不同的照明条件之间进行转换，白天到晚上，
black and white to color,
从黑白到彩色，
outlines to a colored photo.
轮廓再到彩色照片。
All these cases,
所有这些案例，
and I think in particular the, the most interesting and impactful to me is
特别是对我来说最有趣和最有影响力的是，
this translation between street view and aerial view,
街景和鸟瞰之间的转换，
and this is used to consider,
这是用来考虑，
for example, if you have data from Google maps,
例如，如果你有来自谷歌地图的数据，
how you can go between a street view of the map to the aerial image of that.
你如何在地图的街景和航拍图像之间移动。
Finally, again extending the same concept of translation between one domain to another,
最后，再次扩展一个域到另一个域转换的概念，
another idea is that of completely unpaired translation,
另一个想法是完全不成对的转换，
and this uses a particular GAN architecture, called CycleGAN.
这使用了一种特定 GAN 体系结构，称为 CycleGAN 。
So in this video that I'm showing here,
在我在这里展示的这段视频中，
the model takes as input a bunch of images in one domain,
模型将一个域中的一组图像作为输入，
and it doesn't necessarily have to have a corresponding image in another target domain,
它并不一定要在另一个目标域中有对应的图像，
but it is trained to try to generate examples in that target domain that roughly correspond to the source domain,
但它被训练成试图在该目标域中生成大致对应于源域的示例，
transferring the style of the source onto the target and vice versa.
将源的样式转移到目标上，反之亦然。
So this example is showing the translation of images in horse domain to zebra domain,
所以这个例子展示了从马域到斑马域的图像转换，
the concept here is this cyclic dependency, right,
这里的概念是循环依赖，
you have two GANs that are connected together via this cyclic loss,
你有两个 GAN 通过这个循环损失连接在一起，
transforming between one domain and another.
在一个域和另一个域之间转换。
And really like all the examples that we've seen so far in this lecture,
像我们到目前为止在这节课上看到的所有例子一样，
the intuition is this idea of distribution transformation,
直觉是分布变换的想法，
normally, with GAN, you're going from noise to some target,
通常情况下，在 GAN 的作用下，你会在循环中从噪声转向某个目标，
with the CycleGAN, you're trying to go from some source distribution,
在 CycleGAN 下，你试着从某些源分布，
some data manifold X to a target distribution, another data manifold Y,
从某些数据流形 X 到目标分布另一个数据流形 Y ，
and this is really, really not only cool,
这真的不仅很酷，
but also powerful in thinking about how we can translate across these different distributions flexibly.
而且在思考我们如何灵活地转换这些不同的分布时也很强大。
And in fact, this allows us to do transformations not only to images,
事实上，这让我们不仅可以对图像进行转换，
but to speech and audio as well,
还可以对语音和音频进行转换，
so in the case of speech and audio,
所以在语音和音频的情况下，
turns out that you can take sound waves represent compactly in a spectrogram image
事实证明你可以利用声波，使用一个压缩语谱图表示，
and use a CycleGAN
然后使用 CycleGAN ，
to then translate and transform speech from one person's voice in one domain to another person's voice in another domain, right,
将语音从一个域中的一个人的声音转换到另一个域中的另一个人的声音，
these are two independent data distributions that we define.
这是我们定义的两个独立的数据分布。
Maybe you're getting a sense of where I'm hinting at, maybe not,
也许你已经明白我在暗示什么，也许不是，
but in fact, this was exactly how we developed the model to synthesize the audio behind Obama's voice,
但这正是我们开发模型来合成奥巴马声音背后的音频的方式，
that we saw in yesterday's introductory lecture,
我们在昨天的入门课中看到的，
what we did was,
我们所做的是，
we trained a CycleGAN
我们训练一个 CycleGAN ，
to take data in Alexander's voice
获取 Alexander 声音中的数据，
and transform it into data in the manifold of Obama's voice,
并将其转换为奥巴马声音中的数据，
so we can visualize how that spectrogram waveform looks like for Alexander's voice versus Obama's voice,
所以我们可以直观地看到 Alexander 的声音和奥巴马的声音的频谱图波形是什么样的，
that was completely synthesized using this CycleGAN approach.
这是完全使用 CycleGAN 方法合成的。
Here at MIT.
在 MIT 。
I replayed it,
我重放了一遍，
okay, but basically what we did was
好的，但基本上我们所做的就是，
Alexander spoke that exact phrase that was played yesterday,
Alexander 说了昨天播放的那个短语，
and we had the train CycleGAN model,
我们有训练 CycleGAN 模型，
and we can deploy it then on that exact audio
然后我们可以把它部署到那个精确的音频上，
to transform it from the domain of Alexander's voice to Obama s voice,
把它从 Alexander 的声音域转换到奥巴马的声音域，
generating the synthetic audio that was played for that video clip.
生成为该视频剪辑播放的合成音频。
Okay, before I accidentally played again,
好的，在我不小心再次播放之前，
I jump now to the summary slide.
我跳到总结幻灯片。
So today in this lecture,
今天，在这节课中，
we've learned deep generative models,
我们学习了深入生成模型，
specifically talking mostly about latent variable models, autoencoders, variational autoencoders,
主要讨论了隐变量模型，自编码器，变分自编码器，
where our goal is to learn this low dimensional latent encoding of the data,
我们的目标是学习数据的低维潜在编码，
as well as generative adversarial networks,
以及生成对抗网络，
where we have these competing generator and discriminator components,
我们有这些相互竞争的生成器和判别器组件，
that are trying to synthesize synthetic examples.
试图合成合成例子。
We've talked about these core foundational generative methods,
我们已经讨论了这些核心的基本生成方法，
but it turns out, as I alluded to in the beginning of the lecture,
但事实证明，就像我在讲座开始时提到的那样，
that in this past year in particular,
特别是在过去的一年里，
we've seen truly, truly tremendous advances in generative modeling,
我们看到了生成建模的真正的巨大进步，
many of which have not been from those two methods,
其中许多并不是来自这两种方法，
those two foundational methods that we described,
我们描述的两种基本方法，
but rather a new approach called diffusion modeling.
而是一种名为扩散模型的新方法。
Diffusion models are driving are the driving tools behind the tremendous advances in generative AI,
扩散模型是推动生成性人工智能巨大进步的驱动工具，
that we've seen in this past year in particular,
特别是在过去的一年里，
these GANs, they're learning these transformations, these encodings,
这些 GAN ，它们正在学习这些转换，这些编码，
but they're largely restricted to generating examples that fall similar to the data space that they've seen before,
但它们在很大程度上被限制在生成类似于他们以前见过的数据空间的例子，
diffusion models have this ability
扩散模型现在有这种能力，
to now hallucinate and envision and imagine completely new objects and instances,
可以幻觉、想象和想象全新的物体和实例，
which we as humans may not have seen or even thought about,
作为人类，我们可能没有见过，甚至没有想过，
parts of the design space that are not covered by the training data.
设计空间的部分没有没有被训练数据覆盖。
So an example here is this AI generated art,
这里的一个例子是人工智能生成的艺术，
which art, if you will,
如果你愿意的话，它是艺术，
which was created by a diffusion model,
它是由扩散模型创建的，
and I think not only does this get at some of the limits and capabilities of these powerful models,
我认为这不仅是为了达到这些强大模型的一些限制和功能，
but also questions about what does it mean to create new instances,
但也有关于创建新实例意味着什么的问题，
what are the limits and bounds of these models,
这些模型的极限和界限是什么，
and how do they,
它们如何，
how can we think about their advances with respect to human capabilities and human intelligence.
我们如何看待它们在人类能力和人类智力方面的进步。
And so I'm, I'm really excited that,
所以，我非常兴奋，
on Thursday in lecture seven on new frontiers in deep learning,
在周四的第七讲，深度学习的新领域，
we're going to take a really deep dive into diffusion models,
我们将深入研究扩散模型，
talk about their fundamentals,
讨论它们的基本原理，
talk about not only applications to images,
不仅讨论图像的应用，
but other fields as well,
也讨论其他领域，
in which we're seeing these models really start to make transformative advances,
我们看到这些模型真正开始取得变革性的进展，
because they are indeed at the very cutting edge and very much the new frontier of generative AI today.
因为它们确实处于当今生成性人工智能的前沿和新前沿。
Alright, so with that,
好的，有了这些，
tease and and hopefully set the stage for lecture seven on Thursday
梳理并希望为周四的第七讲做好准备，
and conclude and remind you all that,
结束并提醒你们，
we have now about an hour for open office hour,
我们现在大约有一个小时的开放办公时间，
time for you to work on your software labs,
是你在软件实验工作的时间，
come to us, ask any questions you may have,
请到我们这里来，提出任何你可能有的问题，
as well as the TAs who will be here as well.
以及助教们也在这里。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。